<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Faqs on Chosen Concept - DK Liao Games</title>
    <link>http://blog.chosenconcept.dev/faq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Faqs on Chosen Concept - DK Liao Games</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 19:07:26 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.chosenconcept.dev/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autopanic FAQ</title>
      <link>http://blog.chosenconcept.dev/faq/autopanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 19:07:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.chosenconcept.dev/faq/autopanic/</guid>
      <description>Created: May 10, 2022
Last Updated April 3, 2023: Here are answers to frequently asked questions about my first game, Autopanic!
What is Autopanic? 🔗Autopanic is fully diegetic twinstick shooter with rogue-like elements in which you need to follow the guidance of an AI to reach the top floor of a mysteries facility. Autopanic aims to deliver some interesting narrative design along with satisfying fast-paced combat.
Rogue-like elements will provide some variance during gameplay and you need to fully learn the mechanics to make it to the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autopanic Zero FAQ</title>
      <link>http://blog.chosenconcept.dev/faq/autopanic-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 19:07:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.chosenconcept.dev/faq/autopanic-zero/</guid>
      <description>Created: May 10, 2022
Last Updated Apri 3, 2023: Here are answers to frequently asked questions about my second game, Autopanic Zero!
Where does Autopanic Zero come from? 🔗Autopanic is originally designed to be a shoot ‘em up when it started, most designs back then are accidentally the same (e.g. survive 30 minutes and stuffs). Here’s an old Reddit post of its early days.
Anyways after wrapping up some core pillars of Autopanic in May 2022, I decided to take a look at this phenomenal game called Vampire Survivor that stormed the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
